<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on pirxthepilot</title>
    <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on pirxthepilot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 15:40:28 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pirxthepilot.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 48: Track</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/12/week-48-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 15:40:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/12/week-48-track/</guid>
      <description>Haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to be productive for a few months due to some significant life events. I probably still wont&amp;rsquo; be able to commit to this project regularly, but here at least is a track I was able to make within the past few weeks. It&amp;rsquo;s one that&amp;rsquo;s also under The Facebook Project.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 29: Track</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/07/week-29-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 09:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/07/week-29-track/</guid>
      <description>This patch started from a Ninjam session from last week. Added and changed some things, and made it part of The Facebook Project. Video and soundcloud track below.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 28: DIY</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/07/week-28-diy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 06:30:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/07/week-28-diy/</guid>
      <description>Back to synth-making last week. This time, it&amp;rsquo;s a Minty Synth!
 Back to synth building. This time, a mini-synth for my four year old.
A post shared by joon (@pirxthepilot) on Jul 16, 2017 at 5:21am PDT
   Soldering done.
A post shared by joon (@pirxthepilot) on Jul 16, 2017 at 7:08am PDT
   Mintysynth!
A post shared by joon (@pirxthepilot) on Jul 16, 2017 at 8:47pm PDT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 27: Ninjam</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/07/week-27-ninjam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 08:11:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/07/week-27-ninjam/</guid>
      <description>Had an hour and forty minute-long ninjam online jam session with a friend. Result:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 26: Modular Tracks</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/07/week-26-modular-tracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 16:57:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/07/week-26-modular-tracks/</guid>
      <description>Two tracks continuing the Facebook project, with a video:
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 25: Modular Jam</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/07/week-25-modular-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 08:11:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/07/week-25-modular-jam/</guid>
      <description>A very late post, documenting last week&amp;rsquo;s music. This is track 4 of the Facebook project:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 24: Modular Tracks</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/06/week-24-modular-tracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 06:54:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/06/week-24-modular-tracks/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I inadvertently started a longish ongoing project by posting on my Facebook timeline that I&amp;rsquo;d make a short piece of music to anyone who leaves a comment on the post. So far, 57 friends have done so.
I immediately started on it, and completed three tracks last week:
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 23: Modular Jam</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/06/week-23-modular-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 06:18:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/06/week-23-modular-jam/</guid>
      <description>I spent too much time working on this track. Exploring the new module, the Morphagene, took almost a week. The rest of the patch came together in a day or two, while several more days were spent pondering on the right take to use, mastering things, listening and re-listening.
Reminder: I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t spend too much time one one thing.
In any case, I am quite pleased with the results.
  Soundcloud:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 22: Modular Jam</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/06/week-22-modular-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 08:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/06/week-22-modular-jam/</guid>
      <description>I started this patch aiming for an ambient tune, but after too many changes (and lack of determination) I opted to focus on testing my newly-acquired sequencer as well. The result is a more traditional subtractive-synth syle jam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 21: Live Scoring</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/05/week-21-live-scoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 21:01:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/05/week-21-live-scoring/</guid>
      <description>Not a significantly productive week last week compared with previous ones, but aside from a few modular patch attempts, I participated in a live scoring Ninjam session with my usual group last weekend. We scored Luis Buñuel and Salvador Dali&amp;rsquo;s Un Chien Andalou (An Andalusian Dog), a surrealist short film from 1929.
I prepared my modular patch for this scoring work a few hours before the actual jam. I was going for some weird, dissonant atmospheric sounds that is very different from the sounds I usually aim for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 20: Coding</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/05/week-20-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 08:53:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/05/week-20-coding/</guid>
      <description>Back to coding this last week, where I wrote Python code for a Ninjam/Slack chat bot:
ninjam-slack-bot on github
 Monitors a Ninjam server and sends notifications to a Slack channel everytime someone logs in. Also reports the count and list of currently logged in users.
 I used Errbot as the chat framework. It&amp;rsquo;s also my first project with Python 3!
I got to revisit the use of the threading library, and learned several new things along the way, the most useful of which is Queue() - indispensable as it provided a very convenient means for the Ninjam-side and Slack-side processes to send messages to each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 19: DIY, Jams</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/05/week-19-diy-jams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 06:49:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/05/week-19-diy-jams/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I started and completed building the Temps Utile. It was a quick and pleasant build - my second one involving surface-mount components, which I now enjoy soldering! To think that I was terrified of it a few months ago.
Some more photos:
 Starting a new project.
A post shared by joon (@pirxthepilot) on May 7, 2017 at 5:08am PDT
   Think I&amp;#39;m getting the hang of soldering surface mount components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 18: Track, Modular Jams</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/05/week-18-track-modular-jams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 19:16:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/05/week-18-track-modular-jams/</guid>
      <description>First, I started working on the actual track for &amp;ldquo;Puzzle Girl&amp;rdquo; - the song I was patching the modular for the past couple of weeks. It&amp;rsquo;s far from finished, but I managed to record a lot, and layout a rough arrangement for the first half of the song. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it at that state and just come back to it after a few weeks.
I also recorded a new version of my modular jam from last week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 17: Modular Jam</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/04/week-17-modular-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 19:16:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/04/week-17-modular-jam/</guid>
      <description>Recorded a live jam of the patch I was working on from 2 weeks back. The main synth loops and bass are from the Aalto softsynth, and the rest are modular.
This set is a combination of hardware and loops in Ableton, so I had the idea of hooking up my trusty old Akai LPD8 so I can mute/unmute tracks. A lot of processing is also done in Ableton - some reverb, lots of compression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 16: Live Coding</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/04/week-16-live-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 06:35:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/04/week-16-live-coding/</guid>
      <description>I was away on vacation most of last week and so could not do the usual weekly proclivities. So instead, I tried to learn some live coding with Tidal Cycles. I meant record a tune out of it, but just did not have the time to complete one.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an attempt for an arpeggiated synth bit based on the Stranger Things theme:
 And another, testing sampling capabilities:
 Live coding has opened up a lot of new avenues for me to explore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 15: Modular Patch</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/04/week-15-modular-patch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 21:56:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/04/week-15-modular-patch/</guid>
      <description>Patch cabled out
A post shared by joon (@pirxthepilot) on Apr 16, 2017 at 3:55pm PDT
  Not much to show except a short video of the patch I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the past week. It&amp;rsquo;s for a tune that I started more than two years ago, and now hope to finish with the help of the modular. It&amp;rsquo;s also the most dense patch I&amp;rsquo;ve made so far - so dense that all the VCA and attenuverted/offset channels have been used up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 14: Website Development</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/04/week-14-website-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 17:27:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/04/week-14-website-development/</guid>
      <description>After two long weeks, the production-ready modulogeek.com website is complete!
  This was created with Hugo and with the Creative theme. And a very big thanks to Google Chrome&amp;rsquo;s developer tools: it is quite a godsend. My work would have been magnitudes harder if not for this nifty invention!
The site is also hosted using what I call &amp;ldquo;future tech&amp;rdquo; (cos I am old and this new way of hosting is novel to me).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 13: Website Development</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/04/week-13-website-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 18:46:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/04/week-13-website-development/</guid>
      <description>Spent the entire last week (and this week as well, so far) making a totally new modulogeek.com website. As with this blog, I am making it with Hugo, and basing it on the Creative Theme. There isn&amp;rsquo;t much in the way of media or links to show, as the site is still in progress, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t put it online yet. Perhaps this week..
Making the new site has been more challenging than making this blog, which was mostly a straightforward theme with minimal customizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12: DIY Eurorack, This Blog!</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/03/week-12-diy-eurorack-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 22:59:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/03/week-12-diy-eurorack-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I started on and completed another DIY project: the Music Thing Chord Organ. It was a really nice, laid back, relaxing build - yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s right, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to a point where I find soldering stuff (the easy ones, at least) strangely comforting.
   I got this kit from Thonk. I also like this shop because it has a good assortment of modular DIY parts. In fact, the jacks and knobs on my previous Ornament &amp;amp; Crime build were from Thonk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11: DIY Eurorack</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/03/week-11-diy-eurorack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/03/week-11-diy-eurorack/</guid>
      <description>A post shared by joon (@pirxthepilot) on Mar 19, 2017 at 5:11pm PDT
 Finally completed my Ornament &amp;amp; Crime build and - suprise! - it works! I started this project half-expecting to fail. I’m very much inspired and encouraged by the result. In the same week, while waiting for the O_C’s teensy to arrive, I built a Frequency Central Power as bench power supply for testing newly-built modules. I also bought a 20,000-count multimeter for more accurate voltage calibrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10: DIY Eurorack, Track</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/03/week-10-diy-eurorack-track/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/03/week-10-diy-eurorack-track/</guid>
      <description>Had a very productive week 10. First, started and completed the Synthrotek RND DIY module. It’s a relatively quick build - only took two days of a couple hours each day to finish.
 A post shared by joon (@pirxthepilot) on Mar 11, 2017 at 6:13am PST
  Next, spent some of the weekend making a simple modular + piano track for the 271st Disquiet Junto to mark the 5th anniversary of Bassel Khartabil’s detention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9: DIY Eurorack Module</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/03/week-9-diy-eurorack-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/03/week-9-diy-eurorack-module/</guid>
      <description>Against wise advice, I went ahead and purchased PCB, panels and components for the DIY module Ornament and Crime (http://ornament-and-cri.me). The functionality of this module and the challenges involved is just too hard to resist. Not only is it my first modular DIY build, it is also my first involving surface mount components!
That took a bit of getting used to. At this point I am pretty OK with the 0805s, but still awkward with the chips and anything that has more than 2 legs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8: Modular Jam</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/02/week-8-modular-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/02/week-8-modular-jam/</guid>
      <description>  Second patch with the 208HP, this time trying my hand at ambient stuff. I started this patch about 2 weeks ago, but it’s undergone several iterations.
The star of this patch is Mutable Instruments’ Rings module, which generates fantastic ambient washes out of oscillators. This module is a keeper, for sure.
And here’s the audio version on soundcloud:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7: DIY Digital Oscilloscope</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/02/week-7-diy-digital-oscilloscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/02/week-7-diy-digital-oscilloscope/</guid>
      <description>Finally managed to acquire the missing capacitor from a nearby Fry’s, so I was able to complete this kit project that I started a few weeks ago. This is a time lapse video from start to finish.
  Finished product:
Showing output from the Erica Synths Pico VCO as I scroll through the various waveforms:
A post shared by joon (@pirxthepilot) on Feb 18, 2017 at 12:47am PST
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: Modular Jam</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/02/week-6-modular-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/02/week-6-modular-jam/</guid>
      <description>  This is the end result from the patch created during week 5, with some additional tweaks. It took me countless takes to arrive at something I am content (but not perfectly happy!) with. Recorded live, then post-processed (EQ, compressors, pseudo-mastering) in Ableton.
And here’s a “radio edit” version, with an additional bell layer track:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: Modular patch</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/02/week-5-modular-patch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/02/week-5-modular-patch/</guid>
      <description>Late post. Finally got my 208hp case last week, and this is the first patch that came out of the new configuration. I planned to finish with a jam at the end of last week, but I wasn’t satisfied with what I have recorded. I have also managed to add some more this morning: what was originally 4 voices has now grown to 5!
Decided to just take my time with this, and just let week 6 be the resulting jam/track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: DIY Digital Oscilloscope</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/01/week-4-diy-digital-oscilloscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/01/week-4-diy-digital-oscilloscope/</guid>
      <description> Started work on the KKmoon DSO138 Digital Oscilloscope kit. More practice for future DIY modular synth modules.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Modular Jam, DIY</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/01/week-3-modular-jam-diy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/01/week-3-modular-jam-diy/</guid>
      <description>  This week’s thing is my most complete track on the modular synth. Also: DIY-built a Poti expander for the Xaoc Batumi, sort of as a practice for future projects. Big thanks to jwm from the muffwiggler forums for providing me with the acrylic panel and instructions.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Modular Jam</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/01/week-2-modular-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/01/week-2-modular-jam/</guid>
      <description>20170112 - &amp;ldquo;Sunday Bloody Sunday&amp;rdquo; from modulogeek on Vimeo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Modular Jam</title>
      <link>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/01/week-1-modular-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pirxthepilot.github.io/blog/2017/01/week-1-modular-jam/</guid>
      <description>Trying my hand at live modular performance. Very basic setup here: 3 voices, minimal modulations, simple sequencer changes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>